pimylifeup.com 2019-06-05

# Disclaimer & Privacy Policy - Pi My Life Up

Date Effective: May 1, 2019

## Contents

  1. Disclaimer
  2. Privacy Policy

## 1\. Disclaimer

### 1.1 Content

The tutorials on pimylifeup.com are published in good faith and are for general information purpose only. While we strive to keep our information up to date, we do not make any warranties about the completeness, reliability and accuracy of this information. Any action you take upon the information on this website is strictly at your own risk. We will not be liable for any losses and damages in connection with the use of our website.

From this website you may find advertising and other links to other sites. While we strive to only provide links to useful and ethical websites. We also have no control over the content and nature of these websites. The links we provide to these other websites do not imply a recommendation for all of the content found on these websites.

### 1.2 Amazon

Pi My Life Up is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com.

### 1.3 Comments

Whilst we encourage you to leave comments on Pi My Life Up it’s important to know this doesn’t guarantee it will be published. All comments are placed into a moderation queue and is also cross-checked with anti-spam technologies. We will  **not**  notify you if the comment is approved or removed. If your comment was removed it is likely to be because of one or multiple of the following reasons.

  *  **Harassment:**  Having a conversation is encouraged but keep in mind to be respectful towards other commenters and the authors of the content posted on this website. Comments in all caps will also be removed.
  *  **Promotional** : If your comment comes across to be super promotional then it is likely to be removed. Try not to speak in a promotional language and drop lots of links.
  *  **Out of context:**  Try to keep comments within the context of the page you’re commenting on.
  *  **Caught in the spam filter:  **Sometimes our anti-spam filters will have false positives and your comment can be automatically removed without us knowing. This is likely to happen if your IP has been flagged as a spammer or the contents of your message is consistent with typical spam.

## 2\. Privacy Policy

Pi My Life Up (“Pi My Life Up”) operates pimylifeup.com and may operate other websites. It is Pi My Life Up policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

### 2.1 Advertising Privacy Statement

This Site is affiliated with AdThrive, LLC (“AdThrive”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  AdThrive uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, AdThrive, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behaviour on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.  Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with AdThrive, Google, and our other third party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

#### 2.1.1 For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or AdThrive related to advertising on the Site, you can contact us at [support@pimylifeup.com](mailto:support@pimylifeup.com) ** ** and contact AdThrive at [info@adthrive.com](mailto:info@adthrive.com). If you wish to see a list of the advertising partners we work with or change which of those partners track your behavior using cookies, click the ad preferences link at the bottom of the site. (Available in the EU.)

### 2.2 Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Pi My Life Up collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Pi My Life Up purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Pi My Life Up visitors use its website.

Pi My Life Up also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on pimylifeup.com. Pi My Life Up only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that commenter IP addresses and email addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog/site where the comment was left.

### 2.3 Comments

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service called Akismet. Akismet may use the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).

### 2.4 Embedded content from other websites

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### 2.5 Affiliate Programs

Pi My Life Up may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the content. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

### 2.6 Sponsored Content Tracking Pixels

Pi My Life Up may engage in sponsored campaigns with various influencer networks, brands, and agencies. All sponsored content is duly disclosed in accordance with the FTC’s requirements. From time to time, these sponsored campaigns utilize tracking pixels (aka web beacons), which may contain cookies to collect data regarding usage and audience. This information is collected by the sponsoring company to track the results of the campaign. No personally identifiable information collected by Pi My Life Up is used in conjunction with these tracking pixels.

### 2.7 Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Pi My Life Up websites choose to interact with Pi My Life Up in ways that require Pi My Life Up to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Pi My Life Up gathers depends on the nature of the interaction.

Pi My Life Up does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities such as commenting.

### 2.8 Google Analytics

We use Google Analytics to analyze the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used to create reports about the use of our website.

Google’s privacy policy is available at: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

### 2.9 Facebook Pixel

We use Facebook pixel to analyze the use of our website. The Facebook pixel is an analytics tool that helps us measure the effectiveness of our Facebook advertising. We use the Facebook pixel to understand the actions people are taking on our website and reach audiences that we care about.

### 2.11 TrackMesh

Pi My Life Up makes use of Trackmesh for optimised delivery of our advertising. No personal information is collected, IPs are not collected.

### 2.12 Jetpack

#### 2.12.1 WordPress.com Stats

Pi My Life Up makes use of wordpress.com stats to analyse the use of our website. We track post and page views, outbound link clicks, referring URLs and search engine terms, and country. The IP address, WordPress.com user ID (if logged in), WordPress.com username (if logged in), user agent, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, browser language, country code is collected.

#### 2.12.2 Protect

In order to check login activity and potentially block fraudulent attempts, the following information is used: attempting user’s IP address, attempting user’s email address/username (i.e. according to the value they were attempting to use during the login process), and all IP-related HTTP headers attached to the attempting user.

### 2.13 Retargeting

From time to time, Pi My Life Up may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market Pi My Life Up. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to Pi My Life Up.

### 2.14 CDN

Pi My Life Up makes use of BunnyCDN (Content Delivery Network) to optimise file delivery.  We may use BunnyCDN to gather and temporarily store visitor log information such as anonymised IP, web address, country code and user agent for the purpose of analyzing, processing, testing and security. For more information visit their privacy policy: <https://bunnycdn.com/privacy>

### 2.15 Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Pi My Life Up discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Pi My Life Up behalf or to provide services available at Pi My Life Up websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Pi My Life Up websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them.

Pi My Life Up will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Pi My Life Up discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Pi My Life Up believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Pi My Life Up, third parties or the public at large.

### 2.16 Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Pi My Life Up uses cookies to help Pi My Life Up identify and track visitors, their usage of Pi My Life Up website, and their website access preferences. Pi My Life Up visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Pi My Life Up websites, with the drawback that certain features of Pi My Life Up websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comm

To summarise, we use cookies for the following purposes:

(a) Authentication: We use cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our website;

(b) Email: We use cookies to help us to send relevant emails to users who have subscribed to our email list;

(c) Security: We use cookies as an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and services generally;

(d) Advertising: We use cookies to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you; and

(e) Analysis: We use cookies to help us to analyze the use and performance of our website and services. These cookies will last for up to one year.

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can, however, obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

#### 2.16.1 Google AdSense and DoubleClick Cookie

Google, as a third-party advertisement vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on Pi My Life Up. The use of DoubleClick cookies by Google enables them to serve adverts to visitors that are based on their visits to this website as well as other sites on the internet.

To opt out of the DoubleClick cookies you may visit the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL  [http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/) Tracking of users through the DoubleClick cookie mechanisms are subject to Google’s own privacy policies.

### 2.17 Business Transfers

If Pi My Life Up, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Pi My Life Up goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Pi My Life Up may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

### 2.18 Email

On Pi My Life Up, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels and links. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows Pi My Life Up to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behaviour will not be passed on to third parties and is only collected by our email processor, Active Campaign.

### 2.19 Purchases

We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into our ecommerce system “WooCommerce”. The Transactional Data may include your contact details, your card details and the transaction details. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions.

Payment processing for Pi My Life Up is handled by our payment services providers, PayPal and Stripe. We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds. You can find information about the payment services providers’ privacy policies and practices at <https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full> and <https://stripe.com/privacy>.

### 2.20 Ads

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Pi My Life Up and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### 2.21 International Transfers

Pi My Life Up may transfer and process Customer Data anywhere in the world where Pi My Life Up or its Sub-processors maintain data processing operations. Pi My Life Up shall at all times provide an adequate level of protection for the Customer Data processed, in accordance with the requirements of Data Protection Laws.

### 2.22 Data Retention

Generally, data is retained until it is no longer useful. For example, we keep the web server logs that record information about a visitor to Pi My Life Up website, such as the visitor’s IP address, browser type, and operating system, for approximately 30 days. We retain the logs for this period of time in order to, among other things, investigate issues if something goes wrong on one of our websites.

### 2.23 What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on Pi My Life Up, or have left comments, signed up to our email list, purchased a product, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

If you are located in certain countries, including those that fall under the scope of the European General Data Protection Regulation (AKA the “GDPR”), data protection laws give you rights with respect to your personal data, subject to any exemptions provided by the law, including the rights to:

  * Request access to your personal data;
  * Request correction or deletion of your personal data;
  * Object to our use and processing of your personal data;
  * Request that we limit our use and processing of your personal data; and
  * Request portability of your personal data.

You can usually access, correct, or delete your personal data using your account settings and tools that we offer, but if you aren’t able to do that, or you would like to contact us about one of the other rights, scroll down to contact us.

EU individuals also have the right to make a complaint to a government supervisory authority.

### 2.24 Security

While no online service is 100% secure, we work very hard to protect information about you against unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction, and take reasonable measures to do so, such as monitoring our Services for potential vulnerabilities and attacks.

To enhance security, Pi My Life Up use of security settings such as two-step authentication (When Available). We also make use of randomized complicated passwords.

### 2.25 Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Pi My Life Up may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Pi My Life Up sole discretion. Pi My Life Up encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If you have a Pi My Life Up.com account, you might also receive an alert informing you of these changes. Your continued use of Pi My Life Up after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

## 2.26 Contact

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the practices of Pi My Life Up, please contact us at [support@pimylifeup.com](mailto:support@pimylifeup.com)

## 2.27 Pi My Life Up Sub Processors

Pi My Life Up currently uses the following sub processors

 **Sub Processor**|  **Service Provided**|  **URL**  
---|---|---  
OVH| Server Provider| https://www.ovh.com  
Azure| Backups| https://azure.microsoft.com  
BunnyCDN| Content Delivery| https://bunnycdn.com/  
Cloudflare| DNS Provider| https://www.cloudflare.com/  
Gmail| Email| https://mail.google.com  
ActiveCampaign| Email| https://www.activecampaign.com/  
Akismet| Spam Protection| https://akismet.com/  
Adthrive| Advertising| https://www.adthrive.com/  
TrackMesh| Advertising/Analytics| https://trackmesh.com/  
Facebook| Analytics| https://facebook.com  
Google Analytics| Analytics| https://analytics.google.com  
WordPress.com| Analytics & Brute Force Protection| https://wordpress.com  
Slack| Notifications| https://slack.com/  
Zendesk| Help Desk Software| https://www.zendesk.com/  
Paypal| Payment Provider| https://www.paypal.com/  
Stripe| Payment Provider| https://stripe.com/
